<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="resources/style/feed.xsl"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Owen's Feed</title>
  <link href="http://owencompher.me"/>
  <link rel="self" href="http://owencompher.me/feed.xml"/>
  <updated>2023-06-18T20:30:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Owen Compher</name>
  </author>
  <id>http://owencompher.me/</id>

  <entry>
    <title>Unnamed origami app</title>
    <link rel="self" href="https://owencompher.me/feed.xml#0005"></link>
    <id>tag:owencompher.me,2023:/feed.xml#0005</id>
    <updated>2023-09-20T22:22:00-04:00</updated>
    <summary>I learn web frameworks and make a thing</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Recently I've gotten back into origami and have rediscovered how annoying it is to find diagrams online. I'm not a huge fan of video tutorials, and other than Jo Nakashima and a few others, YouTube is full of low quality or simple and unoriginal tutorials. <a href="https://www.giladorigami.com">Gilad's Origami Page</a> has a great database of designs and the books they are found in, but in order to access the diagrams I have to hope there is pdf of the book floating around. This can take some time and is of dubious legality. I felt it would be nice if I could pay a few bucks for easy access to online diagrams, instead of relying on piracy or paying $20 and waiting a week for a book full mostly of models I'm not interested in.</p>
      <p>So thats how I got the idea for my most recent project/'learning experience': a website for finding and sharing (or possibly buying and selling) origami diagrams, similar to YouTube or iTunes or Spotify. I knew it would probably be one of my larger projects so I started by learning Docker, then starting with the Laravel framework. It was annoying to set up so I switched to Django and all the configuartion still felt unnescessary so I stopped using Docker and switched to Flask. I liked having more control of the way the project is organized.</p>
      <p>Anyways I'm pretty proud of what I have and put the beta of 'origami app' up at <a href="https://origami.owencompher.me">https://origami.owencompher.me</a> until I come up with a name and get the domain. I also still have a fair amount of things I want to do with the project, including actually finding content I can legally put on the site. If anyone actually reads this and is interested (first of all, hi!) you can make an account on the website and check out the repository at <a href="https://github.com/owencompher/origami-app">https://github.com/owencompher/origami-app</a>.</p>
    </div></content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Online Whiteboard</title>
    <link rel="self" href="https://owencompher.me/feed.xml#0004"></link>
    <id>tag:owencompher.me,2023:/feed.xml#0004</id>
    <updated>2023-07-01T21:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <summary>I made a little web app thing</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>I thought it would be cool to have some place to have a kind of notes.txt file- but on the internet. The idea is that I can easily access it from any device that has a browser and an internet connection. Instead of having a text file on my laptop, and the notes app on my iphone, and emails to myself, I just type into a webpage and click a button, and the content is immediately stored on my cloud sever. I have it up at <a href="https://files.owencompher.me/whiteboard">files.owencompher.me/whiteboard</a>.</p>
      <p>The other property is that it is public. Even if I never find a good use for that fact it is still a pretty cool concept. It's also why I thought 'whiteboard' might be a good name for it; it's kinda like how people put little whiteboards on their dorm room doors for passing classmates to write things on. Right now it's password protected, but if you promise to not grief it the password is "whiteboard-unflexing-oriented-grouse!". I might eventually make a couple different versions, with different levels of privacy/security.</p>
      <p>The tech is pretty simple: PHP to load the text file into a form textarea, and to overwrite the file when submitted with the correct password. I know there's probably some huge security issues, but I'm not too concerned; I don't plan on keeping anything sensitive anywhere near it.</p>
    </div></content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>On the Indie Web</title>
    <link rel="self" href="https://owencompher.me/feed.xml#0003"></link>
    <id>tag:owencompher.me,2023:/feed.xml#0003</id>
    <updated>2023-06-18T20:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <summary>I discuss recent site updates</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>In the last couple of days, I've been exploring the indie web and adding to my website/server. It started with some <a href="https://owencompher.me/feed.xml#0001">interest in feeds</a>, but I've discovered a lot of different little things.</p>
      <p>To subscribe to feeds, I set up the <a href="https://miniflux.app/">Miniflux</a> feed reader on my web server. It works perfectly for what I was looking for, and for the past week I've been adding feeds and using it in addition to reddit, though I want to transition to using it alone. I strongly recommend the software to anyone else who is thinking about self-hosting feed aggregation. You are also welcome to use <a href="https://miniflux.owencompher.me">my instance</a>, if you email me I'll make an account for you.</p>
      <p>I also made an account on status.cafe, and have been using it along with the forum. It was created by m15o, who also made a whole bunch of other things I've come across, almost too many to list. A lot of it is focused on blogging and journaling, like <a href="nightfall.city">nightfall.city</a> and a lot of the things linked on it. I think the general mission of providing small, non-commercial social spaces is admirable, and as I transition away from increasingly <a href="https://pluralistic.net/2023/01/21/potemkin-ai/#hey-guys">enshittified</a> spaces, these sites provide a nice alternative. I've also been thinking about getting into more Mastodon instances.</p>
      <p>Some other things I've done:<br/>
      - a <a href="https://owencompher.me/kiosk">clone</a> of <a href="https://kiosk.nightfall.city/">Neon Kiosk</a><br/>
      - a personal DAViCal server
      </p>
    </div></content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>A Tumblr Post</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://owen-af.tumblr.com/post/711272935892074496"></link>
    <link rel="self" href="https://owencompher.me/feed.xml#0002"></link>
    <id>tag:owencompher.me,2023:/feed.xml#0002</id>
    <updated>2023-06-15T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <summary>Testing content types (Tumblr post)</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      This entry represents a <a href="https://owen-af.tumblr.com/post/711272935892074496">Tumblr post</a>.
    </div></content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Starting my Atom Feed</title>
    <link href="http://owencompher.me/feed.xml#0001"/>
    <id>tag:owencompher.me,2023:/feed.xml#0001</id>
    <updated>2023-06-15T03:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <summary>The first post; about the feed</summary>
    <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Since I've stopped using most social media the last few years, and since the reddit blackout/loss of apollo, I've started subscribing to rss/atom feeds and using that as my main source of entertainment. It has inspired me to create my own feed.</p>
        <p>My idea for content is not to start blogging or making any kind of content, but instead a kind of manual aggregation of anything I post anywhere. Anytime I significantly update/add to my website or post on any social media I will document it or link to it here. If I ever do feel like writing a blog post or publishing some other kind of thing, I could always just do it here, instead of having to find it's own spot for it.</p>
        <p>Basically, I don't think any other categories of content I publish deserve their own feed, so I'm making one for everything. Hopefully that will allow the frequency of posts stay somewhere about once a month.</p>
    </div></content>
  </entry>
</feed>
